
Gimiwan (26 June 2017 [Beta])

   Using the quadratic discharge potential model and observed heads, compute 
   the expected values and standard deviations of the regional uniform recharge, 
   the magnitude of the regional uniform flow, and the direction of the regional 
   uniform flow over ranges of conductivities and thicknesses. 

Usage: 
   Gimiwan <xo> <yo> <k alpha> <k beta> <k count> <h alpha> <h beta> <h count> <radius> <obs filename> <wells filename> <out fileroot> 
   Gimiwan --help 
   Gimiwan --version 

Arguments: 
   <xo>            The x-coordinate [L] of model origin. (xo,yo) is the location 
                   at which the magnitudes and directions of the regional uniform 
                   flow are computed. 

   <yo>            The y-coordinate [L] of model origin. (xo,yo) is the location 
                   at which the magnitudes and directions of the regional uniform 
                   flow are computed. 

   <k_alpha>       The log-mean of the aquifer hydraulic conductivity [ln(L/T)]. 

   <k_beta>        The log-standard deviation of the aquifer hydraulic 
                   conductivity [ln(L/T)]. 

   <k_count>       The number of equal probability intervals for conductivity. 

   <h_alpha>       The log-mean of the aquifer thickness [ln(L)]. 

   <h_beta>        The log-standard deviation of the aquifer thickness [ln(L)]. 

   <h_count>       The number of equal probability intervals for thickness. 

   <radius>        The radius [L] of the buffer circle around of each pumping 
                   well. Any observations located within one or more well's 
                   buffer circle are excluded from the analysis. 

   <obs filename>  The name of the input observation file. 

   <well filename> The name of the input well file. 

   <out fileroot>  The filename root of the six output files. 


Example: 
   Gimiwan 100 200 2.2 0.2 10  2.3 0.10 10 100 obs.csv wells.csv results 

Observation File: 
   All of the observation head data are supplied by this .csv file. 

   The observation file contains no header line. The observation file may 
   include blank lines, which are ignored. The observation may include 
   comment lines, which are identified by an octothorpe (#) in the first 
   column of the line. 

   The observation file contains one line for each head observation. Each 
   line in the observation file has five fields. 

   <ID>            The observation identification string. The ID string can 
                   contain numbers, letters, underscores, and internal spaces. 
                   The ID may not contain commas. 

   <x>             The x-coordinate [L] of observation location. 

   <y>             The y-coordinate [L] of observation location. 

   <head>          The measured head [L]. The head is measured from the base 
                   of the aquifer. The head must be strictly positive. 

   <std dev>       The standard deviation of the measured head [L]. The 
                   standard deviation must be strictly positive. 

   Each of the five fields must separated by a single comma. Spaces and tabs 
   at the start and end of fields are trimmed. 

Well File: 
   All of the pumping well data are supplied by this .csv file. 

   The well file contains no header lines. The well file may include blank 
   lines, which are ignored. The well file may include comment lines, which 
   are identified by an octothorpe (#) in the first column of the line. 

   The well file contains one line for each pumping well. Each line in the 
   well file has five fields. 

   <ID>            The well identification string. The ID string can contain 
                   numbers, letters, underscores, and internal spaces. The ID 
                   may not contain commas. 

   <x>             The x-coordinate [L] of pumping well location. 

   <y>             The y-coordinate [L] of pumping well location. 

   <r>             The radius [L] of the well casing. The radius must be 
                   strictly positive. 

   <Q>             The discharge [L^3/T] (pumping rate) of the well. 

   Each of the five fields must separated by a single comma. Spaces and tabs 
   at the start and end of fields are trimmed. 

Output Files: 
   Gimiwan generates six identically formatted .csv files. Two files, 

      -- expected value file (_ev), and 
      -- standard deviation file (_sd), 

   are generated for each of the three hydrogrologic descriptors, 

      -- regional uniform recharge [L/T], 
      -- magnitude of the regional uniform flow [L^2/T] evaluated at (xo,yo), and 
      -- direction of the regional uniform flow [deg] evaluated at (xo,yo). 

   The names of the six file are constructed from the <out fileroot>. 

      <out fileroot>_recharge_ev.csv 
      <out fileroot>_recharge_sd.csv 

      <out fileroot>_magnitude_ev.csv 
      <out fileroot>_magnitude_sd.csv 

      <out fileroot>_direction_ev.csv 
      <out fileroot>_direction_sd.csv 

   Each file contains a recangular array of values, with k_count+1 rows 
   h_count+1 columns. The first row contains the h values (thicknesses) 
   associated with each column. The first column contains the k values 
   (conductivities) associated with each row. 

Notes: 
   o  The set of observations may include 'duplicates', i.e. multiple 
      observation values at the same location. However, there must be at 
      least 10 unique observation locations remaining after excluding all 
      of the observations within any pumping well's buffer circle. 

   o  The project name 'Gimiwan' is the Ojibwe word for the inanimate 
      intransitive verb 'it rains'. See [http://ojibwe.lib.umn.edu]. 

Authors: 
   R. Barnes, University of Minnesota 
   R. Soule,  Minnesota Department of Health 

